# Apoorva S

## Front End Developer

## Profile

Currently working as software engineer in Tech Mahindra Pvt Ltd (April 2018 - till date). Worked on AngularJs and Angular 2. A good team worker, having strong analytical, problem solving and interpersonal skills. Proficient in web technologies, SDLC (Analysis & design, coding, testing and implementation) and AGILE/SCRUM methodology.

## Work History

2019-07 -Current

### **Software Engineer**

Tech Mahindra, Bangalore, Karnataka

- 1. Requirement analysis
- 2. Code development/enhancement
- 3. Code review
- 4. Junit testing

2018-06 -2019-05

### **Associate Software Engineer**

Tech Mahindra, Bangalore, Karnataka

- 1. Requirement analysis by discussing with BA
- 2. Web application development
- 3. Code review
- 4. Bug fixing

## Project details

2019-07 -Current

#### **DEP-Infra tools**

Tech Mahindra, Bangalore, Karnataka

**Project Description:** The team, DEP – Infra tools is designated to work on all internal applications maintained by the client Thomson Reuters. This included applications that helps in access permissions, applications that maintain a strict record of the operation and performance data of various storage components, applications that help in communicating with client for any orders from the customers etc.

### Contact

#### **Address**

#4, 8th main, 4th block, 2nd phase, BSK III Stage, Girinagara, Bangalore,

Karnataka, 560085

**Phone** 

9591851659

E-mail

apoorvas081@gmail.com

### Skills

**Angular** 

AngularJS

HTML5/CSS

TypeScript

**JavaScript** 

Unix

**Bootstrap** 

## Languages

Kannada

Hindi

**English** 

### Interests

Singing

Doodle

Photography

#### **Client:** Thomson Reuters

- Requirement gathering for any new development work that is provided by the client. Communicate with the business customers to understand the requirement, estimation of time and agreeing to deliver the same on time.
- Working as per the requirement provided, either by writing fresh code to implement the enhancements or by enhancing already existing code.
- Testing the application using Junit when the local code base is pointing to different environments. Fixing bugs if any.
- Maintain versioning of the work with the help of Git-BLIT repository. Tracking the progress of everyday work with the help of JIRA. Estimation of the time required to complete a task before starting the task.

Technologies used: Java

#### 2018-06 -2019-05

### enterprise Governance Risk Compliance

Tech Mahindra, Bangalore, Karnataka

**Project Description:** Enterprise GRC (eGRC) is an integrated solution that addresses the business processes of financial controls management, audit management, operational risk management, enterprise risk management, IT governance, and general compliance. The program is designed to allow organizations to track the ever increasing complexities of the business environment.

#### **Client:** Thomson Reuters

- Evaluated project requirements and specifications and developed software applications that surpassed client expectations.
- Estimated the efforts required using JIRA.
- Migrated the client application from flex to AngularJS using Visual studio code.
- Debugged code and located root causes of problems by reviewing configuration files and logs.
- Reviewed code and committed to SVN repository.

**Technologies used:** AngularJS(1.7) and ELF library(Thomson Reuters Proprietary).

## Education

2010-06 - **SSLC**2011-05 Chinmaya English Me

Chinmaya English Medium High School – Mangalore

2012-06 - **P.U.C. PCMC** 

2013-06 St. Agnes PU College - Mangalore

2013-08 - Bachelor of Engineering in Electrical and Electronics Engineering

St.Joseph Engineering College - Mangalore